In tonight's section of Ifs, quiz about all culture in Sweden:
I kvällens avsnitt av IFS, frågesporten om all kultur i Sverige:
Sweden's most fun Chinese, Evelyn Mok.
Sveriges roligaste kines, Evelyn Mok.
The power -poding perfume profile Filip Dikmen.
Den powerpoddande parfymprofilen Filip Dikmen.
The beach rag from Botkyrka, Thanos Fotas.
Strandraggaren från Botkyrka, Thanos Fotas.
Still Making it Flawless: Samira Ismail.
Still making it flawless: Samira Ismail.
The world's Swedishest Arab, Elaf Ali.
Världens svenskaste arab, Elaf Ali.
IF's brother from Jordbro, Big O.
IFS bror från Jordbro, Big O.
Nanga Def, Bachelorette Olivia Birgersson.
Nanga def, bachelorette Olivia Birgersson.
The dancing Persian prince sausage Sean Banan.
Den dansande persiska prinskorven Sean Banan.
Last but not least, our program manager Ahmed Berhan!
Sist men inte minst, vår programledare Ahmed Berhan!
Welcome to IFS, which caused Suedis to wash in the ass -
Välkommen till IFS, som fick suedis att tvätta sig i röven–
- With Nasty Mac "Nasties".
–med Nasty Mac "nasties".
My name is Ahmed Berhan, The Hostess with the Mostest.
Mitt namn är Ahmed Berhan, the hostess with the mostest.
These are our fantastic competitors.
Det här är våra fantastiska tävlande.
We have, the influence of the pink helicopter, Lars!
Vi har, influgen på den rosa helikoptern, Lars!
No cub, she loves green. An applause for Louise!
Ingen gröngöling, hon älskar grönt. En applåd för Louise!
Train hosts from Hässleholm, at Orange: Johanna!
Tågvärden från Hässleholm, på orange: Johanna!
Welcome. - Lars, you lecture on group dynamics in workplaces.
Välkomna. – Lars, du föreläser om gruppdynamik på arbetsplatser.
How to handle difficult people. What awkward panelists do you take?
Hur man hanterar besvärliga personer. Vilka besvärliga panelister tar du?
- Tranos we start with. - He said Thanos! /Pronounces with "th"/
–Thanos börjar vi med. –Han sa Thanos! /UTTALAR MED "TH"/
- You've been to Kos. Rhodes -88. - He may be your dad.
–Du har varit på Kos. Rhodos -88. –Han kanske är din pappa.
- Tyd, I'm flowing here. - Little Like.
–Tyst, jag flowar här. –Lite likt.
Feels like you have the same hairdresser. Same olive oil.
Känns som att ni har samma frisör. Samma olivolja.
This is just salt water.
Det här är bara saltvatten.
The Turkish steam sauna Hamam is now well established in Sweden.
Den turkiska ångbastun hamam är numera väletablerad i Sverige.
It is probably hammam for transgender people.
Det är väl hamam för transpersoner.
I've never seen so many hold back a laugh. The audience ...
Jag har aldrig sett så många hålla tillbaka ett skratt. Publiken...
/Suffocates laughs/
/KVÄVER SKRATT/
Tamam, it's ... you've heard the word haram?
Tamam, det är... Du har väl hört ordet haram?
If doing any haram, that person becomes tamed. Then there is ...
Om gör nåt haram, blir den personen tamamstämplad. Sen finns det...
You sometimes hear "coktamam". COK means a lot.
Man hör ibland "coktamam". Cok betyder väldigt mycket.
That person is very much haram, or has done a lot of haram.
Den personen är väldigt mycket haram, eller har gjort mycket haram.
Oh! Fantastically explained, but I don't think ... no.
Äh! Fantastiskt förklarat, men jag tror inte... Nej.
- But a fantastic explanation? - Well.
–Men en fantastisk förklaring? –Javisst.
- You think he is lying? -Yes.
–Du tror att han ljuger? –Ja.
Congratulations, Lars, you have received your first point.
Grattis, Lars, du har fått din första poäng.
False. Tamam has neither halal nor haram to do.
Falskt. Tamam har varken med halal eller haram att göra.
Tamam means okay in both Turkish and Arabic. - Tamam?
Tamam betyder okej både inom turkiska och arabiska. – Tamam?
Tamam.
Tamam.
Louise, I heard you love grass. Should you tell me what you are doing?
Louise, jag hörde att du älskar gräs. Ska du berätta vad du gör?
I pick grass, take a loupe and a determination key and check species.
Jag plockar gräs, tar en lupp och en bestämningsnyckel och kollar art.
The man, do you live in the 18th century?
Mannen, bor du på 1700-talet?
- You are a biologist. - You have to explain to them later.
–Du är biolog. –Du får förklara för dem sen.
- What of the panelists are you picking? - I take Filip.
–Vilken av panelisterna plockar du? –Jag tar Filip.
I See You.
I see you.
Hi Svejsan, Svenne!
Hejsan svejsan, svenne!
You use it to communicate DHSS - "We will make a messy evening".
Man använder det för att kommunicera DHSS – "vi ska göra en stökig kväll".
Skåne and Stockholm are different. In Skåne it means "haram, liquor, sex".
Skåne och Stockholm är olika. I Skåne betyder det "haram, sprit, sex".
In Stockholm they say "haram, schlaif, sex". You should go out and make horhus.
I Stockholm säger de "haram, schlaif, sex". Man ska gå ut och göra horhus.
He nods. He just: "I've done it!"
Han nickar. Han bara: "Jag har gjort det!"
Imagine if it was so fun to do horhus.
Tänk om det var så roligt att göra horhus.
In other words, it's a chaotic evening.
Med andra ord, det är en kaosig kväll.
I want to believe you, but think you are lying.
Jag vill tro dig, men tror att du ljuger.
It feels like a strange abbreviation for it.
Det känns som en konstig förkortning för det.
What abbreviation do you have to strangle?
Vad har du för förkortning för att stöka?
! No I do not know.
Partay! Nej, jag vet inte.
You think Filip is lying. You're doing right. Congratulations to your first point.
Du tror Filip ljuger. Du gör rätt. Grattis till din första poäng.
HSS stands for "Hear nothing, see nothing, says nothing." So, don't go.
HSS står för "Hör inget, ser inget, säger inget." Alltså, gola inte.
An abbreviation for "Mind Your Fucking Business". - Johanna?
En förkortning för "mind your fucking business". – Johanna?
- I choose Olivia. - Oh, fine.
–Jag väljer Olivia. –Å, fina.
Olivia?
Olivia?
Bleed.
Blöda.
It's her favorite weeks. She doesn't have to do anything.
Det är hennes favoritveckor. Hon behöver inte göra nånting.
Do not cook, not clean. The man takes care of everything. She gets chill.
Inte laga mat, inte städa. Mannen sköter allt. Hon får chilla.
It's like an Islamic sick leave.
Det är som en islamsk sjukskrivning.
She just: "Yes, I'll convert."
Hon bara: "Yes, jag ska konvertera."
She will google Shahada after this.
Hon kommer att googla Shahada efter det här.
- No, I don't believe you. -Right. You have also received a point.
–Nej, jag tror inte på dig. –Rätt. Du har också fått en poäng.
In Islam, a menstruating woman is considered unclean. She is not allowed to fast-
Inom islam anses en menstruerande kvinna oren. Hon får inte fasta–
- Driver the Qur'an or pray in the mosque. If you bleed, you go to leave.
–röra koranen eller be i moskén. If you bleed, you gots to leave.
- Lars? –Evelyn.
–Lars? –Evelyn.
-Yes thank you. - What is it with Asians and thank you?
–Ja, tack. –Vad är det med asiater och tacka?
You're here to get a fucking question.
Du är här för att få en fucking fråga.
So, I'm bleeding now so I'm ...
Alltså, jag blöder nu så jag är...
I'm very ... All over the place.
Jag är väldigt...all over the place.
That's why I'm dressed like I am feeling.
That's why I've dressed like I am feelings.
–Evelyn? -Yes.
–Evelyn? –Ja.
The important question is well: How long do they intend to stay?
Den viktiga frågan är väl: Hur länge tänker de stanna?
Yes. The thing is ... the first Romans ...
Jo. Grejen är... De första romerna...
It's a little fun indeed. This year, Sweden will be 500 years old.
Det är lite kul faktiskt. I år fyller Sverige 500 år.
But the first Romans have been here since 1512.
Men de första romerna har varit här sen 1512.
So they have been here for 511 years. They have been here longer than Sweden has existed.
Så de varit här i 511 år. De har varit här längre än Sverige funnits.
The question is whether this is Sweden or whether it was Roman from the beginning.
Frågan är om det här är Sverige eller om det var romskt från början.
- mm. But that ... - I think you are right.
–Mm. Men det... –Jag tror du har rätt.
You guess what Evelyn says is true.
Du gissar på att det Evelyn säger är sant.
Congratulations, Lars. You've got one more point.
Grattis, Lars. Du har fått en till poäng.
30 Roma families came to Stockholm in 1512, according to an old protocol.
30 romska familjer kom till Stockholm 1512, enligt ett gammalt protokoll.
The first known information about Roma in Sweden, and the first Rome Register.
Den första kända uppgiften om romer i Sverige, och första romregistret.
But definitely not the last. Congratulations to your second score.
Men definitivt inte det sista. Grattis till din andra poäng.
- We move on to Louise. –Yes. Then I take Samira.
–Vi går vidare till Louise. –Yes. Då tar jag Samira.
Samira?
Samira?
Blood pudding.
Blodpudding.
- Check, how happy Thanos became. –Wa? Nämen, this is how it is.
–Kolla, hur glad Thanos blev. –Va? Nämen, så här är det.
Many Somalis move back, or return, to Somalia.
Många somalier flyttar tillbaka, eller återvandrar, till Somalia.
They have brought food with them. O'boy, buns and blood pudding.
De har haft med sig mat. O'boy, bullar och blodpudding.
- Well! - No?
–Näe! –Näe?
I don't actually believe it.
Jag tror inte på det faktiskt.
Think about how many animals are in Somalia that can make ... the dish.
Tänk på hur många djur som finns i Somalia som kan göra...maträtten.
- I think you are lying. - She knows that blood pudding is disgusting.
–Jag tror du ljuger. –Hon vet att blodpudding är äckligt.
Congratulations!
Grattis!
Louise has received one more point.
Louise har fått en till poäng.
Baasto is spaghetti and minced meat sauce.
Baasto är spagetti och köttfärssås.
Italy colonized Somalia in the late 19th century and affected the food.
Italien koloniserade Somalia i slutet av 1800-talet och påverkade maten.
It flows well. 2–2–1. Are you going to bring home a point, Johanna?
Det flyter på bra. 2–2–1. Ska du kamma hem en poäng, Johanna?
- What do you choose? - Sea.
–Vem väljer du? –Sean.
Hello Sweden.
Hej, Sverige.
Chos-e file is Persian for popcorn.
Chos-e-fil är persiska för popcorn.
- Elephant bar. -For real?
–Elefantprutt. –På riktigt?
Yes.
Ja.
–That's it? -In other words...
–That's it? –Alltså...
The company that exported popcorn to Iran was called Chesterfield.
Företaget som exporterade popcorn till Iran hette Chesterfield.
We Iranians are joking with them, so we call it Chos-e file. Elephant bar.
Vi iranier skämtar med dem, så vi kallar det chos-e-fil. Elefantprutt.
It sounds too sick to be true, so I think it's true.
Det låter för sjukt för att vara sant, så jag tror det är sant.
You think they call popcorn for elephant bar?
Du tror att de kallar popcorn för elefantprutt?
Congratulations, Johanna, you got one more point!
Grattis, Johanna, du fick en till poäng!
C.Sangla-laj-la-laj-la-laj
La-laj-la-laj-la-laj
I love Persian. They look at popcorn and think elephant.
Jag älskar persiska. De kollar på popcorn och tänker elefantgött.
Who doesn't like elephant guy, yes? In other words...
Vem gillar inte elefantgött, ja? Alltså...
-Lars, take it away. –Alaf.
–Lars, take it away. –Elaf.
Yes.
Yes.
Yes...
Ja...
When immigrants came to Sweden and would receive their social security number -
När invandrare kom till Sverige och skulle få sitt personnummer–
- But they did not know when they were born, they had to go to the Immigration Service -
–men inte visste när de var födda, fick de gå till Invandrarverket–
- And speculate when they were born.
–och spekulera i när de föddes.
Those who thought they were born at the beginning of the year received January 1st -
De som trodde att de var födda i början på året fick 1 januari–
-And those who had late year-Vibe received July 1 as a social security number.
–och de som hade sent på året-vibe fick 1 juli som personnummer.
- When were you born, Lars? –6 October.
–När är du född, Lars? –6 oktober.
-You are swedish. -It is right. I believe you are right.
–Du är svensk. –Det är rätt. Jag tror du har rätt.
Congratulations, Lars. Another point. Awesome work.
Grattis, Lars. Ännu en poäng. Grymt jobbat.
What Elaf told us is true.
Det Elaf berättade är sant.
Immigrants who have not known about their date of birth have received on 1 January -
Invandrare som inte känt till sitt födelsedatum har fått den 1 januari–
- If they were born at the beginning of the year, and July 1 during the second half.
–om de fötts i början av året, och den 1 juli under den andra halvan.
Check out your Facebook's birthday buddies on January 1st-
Kolla på dina Facebook- födelsedagskompisar den 1 januari–
–And see if you find someone named Gustav, Lena or Ingrid. - Louise?
–och se om du hittar nån som heter Gustav, Lena eller Ingrid. – Louise?
- It's just one left. Big O. - Skåne: Is it good with you?
–Det är bara en kvar. Big O. –Skånska: Är det bra med dig?
Skåne: Yes, that's good with me.
Skånska: Ja, det är bra med mig.
Big o, time for a video question.
Big O, dags för en videofråga.
/Ululates/
/ULULERAR/
- brother, where did I end up? -It's not ... /cords with the tongue /
–Bror, var har jag hamnat? –Det är inte... /SLADDRAR MED TUNGAN/
I have to go home and eat. Mom shouts.
Jag måste hem och äta. Mamma ropar.
This is how we immigrants celebrate when we get a permanent residence permit.
Det är så vi invandrare firar när vi får permanent uppehållstillstånd.
- "Congratulations, here is your 0101." -Exactly.
–"Grattis, här är ditt 0101." –Exakt.
No, but it's an old warning sound.
Nej, men det är ett gammalt varningsljud.
When people lived in old villages and it was Robbish, robbery, going on -
När folk bodde i gamla byar och det var robbish, rån, på gång–
- They made the sound. "Come on, we're going to catch shonun. We'll yeah."
–gjorde de ljudet. "Kom, vi ska catcha shonun. Vi ska japp han."
Do you understand?
Förstår du?
Crime is committed. They made that sound to help, listen.
Det begås brott. De gjorde det ljudet för att hjälpas åt, hörru.
- Yes, you are used to. - Tyst, yes!
–Ja, ni är vana. –Tyst, jao!
Filip, Filip! - Walla, I back you, brother.
Filip, Filip! – Walla, jag bakk dig, bror.
- A season I was with her. -Virus?
–En säsong jag var med henne. –Virus?
- It's worse than Corona. - Should we give Louise the chance to answer?
–Det är värre än corona. –Ska vi ge Louise chans att svara?
- I think it's false. - Strange voice: Aha.
–Jag tror det är falskt. –Konstig röst: Aha.
It was astonishing, hearing.
Det var ju häpnadsväckande, hörru.
–Louise, you think it's false? -Yes.
–Louise, du tror att det är falskt? –Ja.
Good job, you've got one more point.
Bra jobbat, du har fått en till poäng.
It's false. Zaghrouta in Arabic is a sound to show joy.
Det är falskt. Zaghrouta på arabiska är ett ljud för att visa glädje.
There is one for Zaghrouta clips, for who gets enough of Zaghrouta?
Det finns ett till zaghrouta-klipp, för vem får nog av zaghrouta?
I can not take it.
Jag orkar inte.
YES! My ladies and gentlemen, as you see right now: full pot, full pot ...
Yes! Mina damer och herrar, som ni ser just nu: Full pott, full pott...
You have a question left, but the whole panel is consumed.
Du har en fråga kvar, men hela panelen är förbrukad.
Therefore, your last panelist will be ...
Därför kommer din sista panelist att vara...
Evelyn.
Evelyn.
- It's the first time I am. - Why are you lying for?!
–Det är första gången jag blir det. –Varför ljuger du för?!
You traveled 31 times during the pandemic. You were stopped at the airport.
Du reste 31 gånger under pandemin. Du blev stoppad på flygplatsen.
Image question: What is the name of this serial album?
Bildfråga: Vad heter det här seriealbumet?
Teddy bear and Kalle Black Skull.
Bamse och Kalle Svartskalle.
It sounds incredible, but that's true.
Det låter otroligt, men det är sant.
It was an edition of Bamse as the Immigration Agency then -
Det var en utgåva av Bamse som Invandrarverket då–
- It was called the Migration Board at the time ...
–det som Migrationsverket hette på dåtiden...
They released this series to counteract that children at school -
De gav ut denna serie för att motverka att barn i skolan–
- Bully immigrant children. They thought it was a good idea.
–mobbade invandrarbarn. De tyckte att det var en bra idé.
It was difficult. You are very convincing too.
Den var svår. Du är väldigt övertygande också.
Thanks.
Tack.
- Well. Well, that's not true. - You don't think so? Okay.
–Näe. Nä, det är inte sant. –Du tror inte det? Okej.
- Unfortunately, Johanna. No point. - Yes, that was true.
–Tyvärr, Johanna. Ingen poäng. –Ja, det var sant.
It's true. Evelyn did not lie.
Det är sant. Evelyn ljög inte.
The series album was named Bamse and Kalle Black Skull -
Seriealbumet hette Bamse och Kalle Svartskalle–
- And was awarded in 1988 in schools by the Swedish National Immigration Service.
–och delades ut 1988 i skolor av Statens invandrarverk.
The integration went really well there.
Integrationen gick jättebra där.
Unfortunately, you only got 2 points. Thank you for joining. You don't move on.
Du fick tyvärr bara 2 poäng. Tack för att du var med. Du går inte vidare.
A large applause to Johanna, and to Lars and Louise who go to the final.
En stor applåd till Johanna, och till Lars och Louise som går till finalen.
Time for the final round. We have our finalists, Lars and Louise.
Dags för finalomgång. Vi har våra finalister, Lars och Louise.
Louise, you may start. It's like the first round -
Louise, du får börja. Det är som första omgången–
- Fast first to 5. If you answer the wrong, the point goes to the opponent.
–fast först till 5. Om du svarar fel går poängen till motståndaren.
- Who do you choose to start with? - I choose Olivia.
–Vem väljer du att börja med? –Jag väljer Olivia.
- Oh, what a honor. Thanks! -Olivia?
–Oj, vilken ära. Tack! –Olivia?
An expression of sex addicts who love to have sex in different places.
Ett uttryck för sexmissbrukare som älskar att ha sex på olika platser.
Outdoors, public places, with lots of people, the Eiffel Tower ...
Utomhus, offentliga platser, med massa personer, Eiffeltornet...
Like Filip.
Som Filip.
- Or like Olivia Bachelorette. - All: Oh!
–Eller som Olivia Bachelorette. –Alla: Ååh!
Oh! We went there!
Åh! Vi gick dit!
- What did you say it was called? - "Hunting Rabbit".
–Vad sa du att det hette? –"Jaga kanin".
Well, that sounds unlikely. I think it's false.
Nä, det låter osannolikt. Jag tror det är falskt.
- You don't think people have sex outdoors? -Yes.
–Du tror inte folk har sex utomhus? –Jo.
But not that it is called "chase rabbit"?
Men inte att det kallas "jaga kanin"?
You do that right in. Congratulations, Louise!
Det gör du helt rätt i. Grattis, Louise!
"Rabbit" means SEK 1 million.
"Kanin" betyder en miljon kronor.
It has nothing to do with it, but rabbit tastes chicken.
Det har inget med saken att göra, men kanin smakar kyckling.
So you know.
Så att ni vet.
- Lars? Who do you choose? - Sea.
–Lars? Vem väljer du? –Sean.
-Hello Sweden. -Hey you.
–Hej, Sverige. –Hej, du.
You need to remind yourself which country you are in.
Du behöver påminna dig om vilket land du är i.
You might go out.
Man kanske åker ut.
If you are invited to dinner by an Indian ...
Om du bjuds på middag av en indier...
Naan of your business.
Naan of your business.
Ah, I took a chance!
Äh, jag chansade!
This is how it is. The Indians were colonized by the British.
Så här ligger det till. Indierna vart koloniserade av britterna.
The British brought forks and knives.
Britterna tog med gafflar och knivar.
The Indians said, "What are you doing here? We're not going to be like you."
Indierna sa: "Vad gör ni här? Vi ska inte bli som er."
"We eat with our hands and feet."
"Vi äter med händerna och fötterna."
It has stuck and become a cultural thing, resistance.
Det har fastnat och blivit en kulturell grej, motståndsgrej–
- To show: "We don't eat with a knife and fork. Fight the power."
–för att visa: "Vi äter inte med kniv och gaffel. Fight the power."
The explanation was completely crazy. But in some way that's right, I think.
Förklaringen var helt galen. Men på nåt sätt är det rätt, tror jag.
Does the Indians eat with their hands like an "act of rebellion"?
Äter indierna med händerna som en "act of rebellion"?
Congratulations, Louise! You've got one more point.
Grattis, Louise! Du har fått en till poäng.
False. They eat with their fingers because it gives a more perfect dining experience.
Falskt. De äter med fingrarna för det ger en mer fullkomlig matupplevelse.
- Drecks on which you dry with. - You are not allowed to eat with the left.
–Beror på vilken man torkar sig med. –Man får inte äta med vänster.
- There is an Indian saying ... - Wait, I'll just record.
–Det finns ett indiskt talesätt... –Vänta, jag ska bara anteckna.
Thanks, Thanos.
Tack, Thanos.
-I'm ready. - Giantbra. We can record too.
–Jag är redo. –Jättebra. Vi kan spela in också.
- It sounds like this ... –Yes?
–Det lyder så här... –Ja?
Eating with a knife and fork is like watching one's beloved through an interpreter.
Äta med kniv och gaffel är som att uppvakta sin älskade genom en tolk.
- Who says this? - A Indian saying.
–Vem säger det här? –Ett indiskt talesätt.
I didn't hang out.
Jag hängde inte med.
- Thanks so much, Elaf. -You are welcome.
–Tack så mycket, Elaf. –Varsågod.
- Louise? - What should I choose?
–Louise? –Vem ska jag välja?
-Thanos. –OKay, Frank.
–Thanos. –Okay, Frank.
Thanos, what happens? How are you?
Thanos, vad händer? Hur mår du?
I have a question for you, brother.
Jag har en fråga till dig, bror.
11 September.
11 september.
Aaah!
Aaah!
- See, the man. You are rough, the man. -Listen! I'm done there.
–Ey, mannen. Du är grov, mannen. –Lyssna! Jag är klar där.
I have nothing more to say. I know it was fantastic.
Jag har inget mer att säga. Jag vet att det var fantastiskt sagt.
-True or false? - It can't be true.
–Sant eller falskt? –Det kan väl inte stämma.
- You think Thanos is lying? -Yes.
–Du tror att Thanos ljuger? –Ja.
Louise, you just gave a point to Lars.
Louise, du gav precis en poäng till Lars.
- you?! -What the hell?!
–Va?! –Vad fan?!
You're joking!
Du skojar! Du skojar!
Wait! They want to know!
Vänta! De vill veta!
-I will explain. Wait. - See them, Ahmed!
–Jag ska förklara. Vänta. –Säg till dem, Ahmed!
It's true. September 11 is the Kebab's day.
Det är sant. 11 september är kebabens dag.
But it's a bit like the chicken and the egg. Which came first?
Men det är lite som hönan och ägget. Vilket kom först?
The Kebab's day came first. 1980, September 11.
Kebabens dag kom först. 1980, 11 september.
-Yes Yes. -Exactly.
–Ja, ja. –Exakt.
So they bombed "9/11" during the Kebab's day?
Så de bombade "9/11" under kebabens dag?
Yes. A pilot just thought they would have a kebab.
Ja. En pilot trodde bara att de skulle haffa kebab.
Had the United States been aware of the day, "9/11" would not have happened.
Hade USA haft koll på dagen hade inte "9/11" hänt.
He might use his notes.
Han kanske skulle använda hans anteckningar.
Kebabens Day was established during the 1980s, September 11.
Kebabens dag etablerades under 80-talet, 11 september.
Too bad we don't celebrate it anymore, then.
Synd att vi inte firar den mer, då.
Take it easy. I don't want to be cancelled.
Ta det lugnt. Jag vill inte bli cancellad.
You can celebrate. Just buying two kebab rolls.
Du kan fira. Bara att du köper två kebabrullar.
Aah!
Aah!
- Many people there. - I had to think.
–Många människor där. –Jag var tvungen att tänka.
But then I sharked! Two kebab rolls. Yes Yes.
Men sen hajade jag! Två kebabrullar. Ja, ja.
-I do not get it. - It's two towers.
–Jag fattar inte. –Det är två torn.
- Yeah! - Now you understand.
–Jaha! –Nu du förstå.
Strong break: You say Chinese are very smart. Now you understand!
Stark brytning: Man säger kineser är jättesmarta. Nu du förstå!
It's because she bleeds. She has no blood in the brain.
Det är för att hon blöder. Hon har inget blod i hjärnan.
- Lars? - Filip.
–Lars? –Filip.
- What do you choose? -Me. Where the hell are you?
–Vem väljer du? –Mig. Var fan är du?
A video question.
En videofråga.
I swear, I've paid. Kus Uktak Sharmota Telhas Tizi.
Jag svär, jag har betalat. Kus ukhtak sharmota telhas tizi.
We saw the entrepreneur and politician Jan Emanuel react negative -
Vi såg företagaren och politikern Jan Emanuel reagera negativt–
-On a parking fine, and started talking another language.
–på en p-böter, och började prata ett annat språk.
He swore in Arabic. Words I don't repeat without getting a slipper at home.
Han svor på arabiska. Ord jag inte upprepar utan att få en toffla hemma.
A nice mix of, simplified expressed, "a little prostitution-vibes".
En skön blandning av, förenklat uttryckt, "lite prostitution-vibes".
A mixture of buttocks, genitals and relatives in a lovely mix.
En blandning av rumphål, könsorgan och släktingar i en härlig mix.
Aah ...
Aah...
You usually mix religion and filth in really good swearing.
Man brukar blanda religion och snusk i riktigt bra svordomar.
- He is serious, he knows. - You think that's true?
–Han är seriös, han vet. –Du tror det är sant?
Lars said what Filip described was true. - Congratulations, Lars. A point.
Lars sa att det Filip beskrev var sant. – Grattis, Lars. En poäng.
Jan Emanuel swore in Arabic with a mixture of various swearing -in
Jan Emanuel svor på arabiska med en blandning av diverse svordomar–
- But his Arabic grammar was Bäh.
–men hans arabiska grammatik var bäh.
- Louise? -Yes. Then I take Elaf.
–Louise? –Ja. Då tar jag Elaf.
It is actually he who you can thank for -
Det är faktiskt han som man kan tacka för–
- That people like Olivia are here.
–att människor som Olivia här finns.
All stylish half -gambians and half -Swedes.
Alla snygga halvgambianer och halvsvenskar.
He started charter tourism between Sweden and Gambia.
Han startade charterturismen mellan Sverige och Gambia.
And a lot of single moms.
Och en massa ensamstående mammor.
Olivia will lower you afterwards.
Olivia kommer att sänka dig efteråt.
That is certainly true. Sounds sick, but I choose to believe you.
Det är säkert sant. Låter sjukt, men jag väljer att tro på dig.
-Racist. - You choose to believe ...?
–Rasist. –Du väljer att tro...?
How nice.
Vad fint.
Despite Elaf's explanation, you were right to believe in her. Congratulations!
Trots Elafs förklaring gjorde du rätt i att tro på henne. Grattis!
You got one more point.
Du fick en till poäng.
Santo.
Santo.
Harding launched charter tourism to Gambia in the mid-60s.
Harding lanserade charterturism till Gambia i mitten av 60-talet.
The father of gambian tourism.
Den gambianska turismens fader.
The highway is Bertil Harding Highway.
Motorvägen heter Bertil Harding Highway.
Congratulations, Louise. - On to you, Lars.
Grattis, Louise. – Vidare till dig, Lars.
- Samira. -Hello.
–Samira. –Hej.
If you go on a date with a South Korean ...
Om du går du på dejt med en sydkorean...
Who said I can't go on a date with a South Korean?
Vem har sagt att jag inte kan gå på en dejt med en sydkorean?
Yalla. Sorry.
Yalla. Förlåt.
If they want to turn kidneys.
Ifall de vill sno njurar.
It's okay, it was I who wrote that joke. It's okay.
Det är okej, det var jag som skrev det skämtet. It's okay.
It's true. For in South Korea–
Det är sant. För i Sydkorea–
- Can not take organs or blood that is not of your family.
–kan man inte ta organ eller blod som inte är av din släkt.
Therefore, I need to know your blood group if I need something from you.
Därför måste jag veta din blodgrupp om jag skulle behöva något från dig.
I don't think you ask it on a date, but you are right.
Jag tror inte du frågar det på en dejt, men du har rätt.
Unfortunately, Lars, it was false.
Tyvärr, Lars, det var falskt.
Congratulations, Louise. One more point.
Grattis, Louise. En till poäng.
South Koreans ask for blood type on dating -
Sydkoreaner frågar efter blodtyp på dejter–
- Because they think it can determine how to match as a person.
–för att de tror att det kan avgöra hur man matchar som person.
It is their horoscope garden.
Det är deras horoskops-gäris.
"Are you an astronaut?" It's not a zodiac sign. Sorry.
"Är du astronaut?" Det är inget stjärntecken. Förlåt.
Are you an astronaut? Huh?
Är du astronaut? Va?
So, it's just something mentally.
Alltså, det är bara nåt psykiskt.
Hey ...
Hey...
Now, as we see on the scoreboard, Louise has four points.
Nu, som vi ser på poängtavlan, har Louise fyra poäng.
If you answer correctly, you win the whole thing.
Om du svarar rätt, vinner du hela grejen.
Okay. Who should I choose? - Then I trust you, Evelyn.
Okej. Vem ska jag välja? – Då litar jag på dig, Evelyn.
-Thanks. –Evelyn?
–Tack. –Evelyn?
What Thanos shouts when he comes.
Det Thanos ropar när han kommer.
Surely, Thanos feels like a guy who looks in the mirror when he comes?
Visst känns Thanos som en kille som kollar sig i spegeln när han kommer?
/Ahmed moans/
/AHMED STÖNAR/
- fun. - Trauma treatment after this.
–Kul. –Traumabehandling efter det här.
Fakelaki is something that you have heard when you have vacationed in Greece.
Fakelaki är nåt som man har hört när man har semestrat i Grekland.
Or, I've heard it.
Eller, jag har hört det.
It is a term for a Greek guy who goes home with the women.
Det är en term för en grekisk snubbe som går hem med kvinnorna.
A Greek Player.
En grekisk player.
You hear fuck. It is English, but you have Greek it a bit.
Man hör fuck. Det är engelska, men man har grekifierat det lite.
Fake-laki. Not to be confused with Asian "Fucky Lucky Long Time".
Fake-laki. Not to be confused med asiatiska "Fucky lucky long time".
So ... it is greek.
Så... It is greek.
- No ... I don't believe that. - You think it's false.
–Näe... Det tror jag inte på. –Du tror att det är falskt.
You seem safe. Have you met a Greek beach raw?
Du verkar säker. Har du träffat en grekisk strandraggare?
-No never. - She answered, then ... /stifled giggly /
–Nej, aldrig. –Hon svarade, sen... /KVÄVT FNISS/
"No, don't talk about stavros anymore."
"Nej, prata inte om Stavros längre."
- You think it's false? -Yes.
–Du tror att det är falskt? –Ja.
Fakelaki means little envelope.
Fakelaki betyder litet kuvert.
It is called bribery to get better service.
Det kallas mutor för att få bättre service.
Louise has received one more point. Congratulations, you have won the whole thing!
Louise har fått en till poäng. Grattis, du har vunnit hela grejen!
/ Samira ululates/ Here you have your diploma.
/SAMIRA ULULERAR/ Här har du ditt diplom.
Here you have your personal edition of Bamse and Kalle Black Skull.
Här har du din personliga utgåva av Bamse och Kalle Svartskalle.
Congratulations, Louise! A large applause to Lars, our panel-
Grattis, Louise! En stor applåd till Lars, vår panel–
- Our audience and to you at home. See you again soon.
–vår publik och till er därhemma. Vi ses snart igen.
OOOH!
Oooh!
Texting: Cristel Nyqvist Swedish Media Text for SVT
Textning: Cristel Nyqvist Svensk Medietext för SVT